Guide to the Joseph Conrad Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Papers, 1862-1957; 6.68; (17 boxes)
  - Papers Relating to Conrad
    - Loumeau, F. R., 1931 June 20 (Box 38)
    - Lubbock, Alfred Basil, 1925 October (Box 38)
    - Lucas, Edward Verrell, 1926 (Box 38)
    - MacDonald, James Ramsay, 1925 October 9 (Box 38)
    - McFee, William, 1925-1926, undated; 3 (Box 38)
    - Machen, Arthur, 1928 January 6 (Box 38)
    - Mallet, Robert, 1945-1946 (Box 38)
    - Mathelin, G., 1956 March 29 (Box 38)
    - Maratray, R. de, 1925 April 1 (Box 38)
    - Marcaggi, J. B., 1927 May 21 (Box 38)
    - Martin, Kingsley, 1935 June 27 (Box 38)
    - Mauron, Charles, 1947 July 18 (Box 38)
    - Meredith, Gertrude O'Day, 1925 August 19 (Box 38)
    - Methuen & Co., Ltd., 1915 February 9 (Box 39)
    - Mondor, Henri, 1956 March 12 (Box 39)
    - Montrésoz, Konstancja (Lubowidska) de, 1927 (Box 39)
    - Moore, George, undated (Box 39)
    - Murchie, Roy, 1924 November 14 (Box 39)
    - Niven, John C., 1925 September 14 (Box 39)
    - Neel, Philippe, 1933, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - Nouveau, Louis H., 1927 October (Box 39)
    - O'Flaherty, Liam, 1928 March 31 (Box 39)
    - Oudard, Georges, 1947-1957; 2 (Box 39)
    - Pastor, P. Emilien, 1931 July 14 (Box 39)
    - Perdraud, E., 1931 July 6 (Box 39)
    - Peyre, Henri, 1946 April 22 (Box 39)
    - Phillips, A. W., 1924 September 30 (Box 39)
    - Potocka, Krystyna, 1927 February 15 (Box 39)
    - Quéant, Olivier, undated (Box 39)
    - Reifenberg, Marijla, 1947 June 15 (Box 39)
    - Reyes, Alfonso, 1956 March 31 (Box 39)
    - Reynolds, Mabel Edith (Galsworthy), 1925 May 5 (Box 39)
    - Rider, Dan J., 1930 (Box 39)
    - Rivoallan, Anatole, 1930-1932 (Box 39)
    - Roberts, Cecil, 1924 December 31 (Box 39)
    - Roberts, Walter Adolph, 1924 November 24 (Box 39)
    - Roché, Louis, 1924-1930; 2 (Box 39)
    - Rothenstein, William, 1925-1927 (Box 39)
    - Ruchon, François, 1930 August 25 (Box 39)
    - Salmon, Arthur L., 1924 November 29 (Box 39)
    - Sandeman, Christopher, 1925 (Box 39)
    - Sanderson, Edward Lancelot, 1925 (Box 39)
    - Savery, Frank, 1927 January 15 (Box 39)
    - Schmidt, Joseph, 1931 July 29 (Box 39)
    - Scott-Moncrieff, Charles Kenneth, 1924 November 11 (Box 39)
    - Sébastien, Robert, 1956 March 12 (Box 39)
    - Séligman-Lu, Geneviève, 1925 October 18 (Box 39)
    - Serafinowica, Leszek Jósef, undated (Box 39)
    - Siegfried, André, 1947-1956; 2 (Box 39)
    - Sitwell, Osbert, 1947 July 16 (Box 39)
    - Skarszewska, K., 1927 July 5 (Box 39)
    - Sparks, Ashley, 1925 August 3 (Box 39)
    - Spicer-Simson, Theodore, 1927 October 10 (Box 39)
    - Stewart, G., 1925 October 26 (Box 39)
    - Stols, Alexandre Alphonse Marius, 1947 July 16 (Box 39)
    - Strachey, John St. Loe, 1925 (Box 39)
    - Sutherland, John Georgeson, 1924-1927; 2 (Box 39)
    - Syed Mohsin bin S. Al Jaffree Co., 1887 (Box 39)
    - Symons, Alphonse James Albert, 1926 December 6 (Box 39)
    - Symons, Arthur, 1910 August 20 (Box 39)
    - Tarde, Guillaume de, 1947 August 21 (Box 39)
    - Tharaud, J. J., 1947 (Box 39)
    - Thevenet, Jacques, undated (Box 39)
    - Traz, Robert de, 1947 July 1 (Box 39)
    - Unwin, T. Fisher, 1925 February 18 (Box 40)
    - Vallette, Alfred Louis Edmond, 1923 August 11 (Box 40)
    - Waldron, Webb, 1924 November 1 (Box 40)
    - Walpole, Hugh, 1924-1938, undated; 3 (Box 40)
    - Ward, Amelia, 1925 December 16 (Box 40)
    - Warrender, Julian Margaret Maitland, 1925 February 17 (Box 40)
    - Willard, Catherine, 1921 September 1 (Box 40)
    - William Heinemann Ltd., 1925-1928; 3 (Box 40)
    - Winawer, Bruno, 1924 (Box 40)
    - Winter, Andrée, 1956 April 13 (Box 40)
    - Wise, Thomas James, 1921-1928; 3 (Box 40)
    - Wodowski, Alexandre de, 1947 (Box 40)
    - Wohlfahrt, Paul, 1936 May 4 (Box 40)
    - Zaleski, Auguste, 1947 November 4 (Box 40)
    - Zaleski, Zygmunt L., 1927 February 4 (Box 40)
  - Photographs
    - Conrad and Others, 1862-1927, undated; 20 (Box 40)
    - Places, 1890-1927, undated; 4 (Box 40)
    - Other, 1876, undated; 7 (Box 40)
- 2016 Acquisition, 1896-1954, undated; 1919-1924; 0.42; (1 box)
  Organized into two groupings: Correspondence and Other Papers.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  From the collection of Stanley J. Seeger. Purchased from R. A. Gekoski on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2016.
  The 2016 acquisition consists chiefly of outgoing letters from Conrad to others. Correspondents include: Elbridge L. Adams, J. Harry Benrimo, Edmund Candler, Sidney Colvin, Bernard Holland, James B. Pinker, T. Fisher Unwin, and E. H. Visiak. In addition, there are two autograph letters, signed, from Jessie Conrad.
  - Correspondence
    - Adams, Elbridge L., 1922-1923 (Box 41)
    - Benrimo, 1922 October 14 (Box 41)
    - Blodgett, Mr., 1923 April 6 (Box 41)
    - Candler, Edmund, 1919 (Box 41)
    - Colvin, [Sidney?], 1919 June 27 (Box 41)
    - Curtiss, Arthur, [1923?] (Box 41)
    - Doubleday, Florence, 1923 June 15 (Box 41)
    - Everett, [John], 1921-1922 (Box 41)
    - [Griffith, William], 1913 February 25 (Box 41)
    - Harrison, [Austin], undated (Box 41)
    - Holland, Bernard, 1922-1923 (Box 41)
    - Janvier, Meredith, 1918 November 6 (Box 41)
    - [Johns], Cloudesley, 1915 June 3 (Box 41)
    - Leo, Reginald H., 1917 February 22; 2 (Box 41)
    - Marshall, Mrs., 1916-1917 (Box 41)
    - Miller, Mr., 1922 January 26 (Box 41)
    - Moore, [Edward], undated (Box 41)
    - Pinker, [James B.?], [1919 July 6?] (Box 41)
    - Quill, Kate Gordon, 1920 August 9 (Box 41)
    - [Retinger, J. H. (Joseph Hieronim)?]; Retinger, Otila, 1919-1920 (Box 41)
    - Ridgeway, [Neville], 1922 November 10 (Box 41)
    - Saltus, [Marie], 1923 February 5 (Box 41)
    - T. Fisher Unwin (Firm), [1896 September 23] (Box 41)
    - Thomason, J. H., 1918 February 2 (Box 41)
    - [Visiak, E. H. (Edward Harold)?], 1924 February 1 (Box 41)
    - Others, 1902-1923, undated (Box 41)
    - Unidentified, 1922, undated (Box 41)
  - Other Papers
    - Autograph manuscript fragments, undated (Box 41)